PATRICK MUTH

Brooklyn, NY | 603-512-7131 | patrickmuth.com | patrick.muth@gmail.com

Creative problem solver with a proven track record of designing highly usable, user-centered experiences. Passion for combining creativity and technology to make people's lives better.

SKILLS

Design, iterate and refine UX concepts through research, interviews, workshops, storyboards, user flows, wireframes, prototyping & user testing. Effectively communicate user experience designs to team members, stakeholders, and present to clients.

Deep knowledge and experience in Figma, Sketch, Framer and Adobe CC

Experience prototyping a variety of interactive projects, including web/mobile, experiential & physical computing.

EXPERIENCE

Service & Interaction Designer, Accenture Song

New York, NY, September 2021 to November 2022

- Designed an interactive prototype for a web-based proprietary B2B transformation tool, conducting stakeholder interviews and a competitor analysis to determine how best to track daily and monthly data and measure that against a project's long-term goals.
- Created a vision plan for modernizing and digitizing the in-person experience for a global non-profit youth education program, using stakeholder interviews and competitor research to determine project requirements.

Senior Experience Designer (Contract), Publicis Sapient

New York, NY, July 2020 to September 2021

 Developed user flows, information architecture and wireframes for updated user management system for a national business-focused telecommunications company, working with multiple teams and stakeholders to combine disparate systems and services into a singular sign-up flow and system

Senior UX Designer (Contract), AKQA

New York, NY, December 2019 to April 2020

- Created user flows and preliminary wireframes for a proof of concept for a new patient scheduling tool for a major US hospital, working with client stakeholders and a technical team to determine project requirements
- Developed information architecture and wireframes for a design system repo for the hospital's new digital component library

Senior Interaction Designer (Contract), Frog Design

Brooklyn, NY, October 2019 to December 2019

 Developed wireframes, information architecture and interactive prototypes (Framer) for the digital launch of a new investment platform for a major American investment group

UX Designer (Contract), Big Spaceship

Brooklyn, NY, September 2019 to October 2019

 Developed wireframes, user flows & competitive analyses for a national satellite radio providers website redesign, focusing on site search and customer account administration

Senior UX Designer (Contract), Valtech

New York, NY, April 2019 to May 2019

- Led user experience on the development of a digital innovation focused concept store for a national makeup brand, creating concepts for new digital interaction for both the in-store and online experience
- Conducted in-person interviews with customers and store employees to develop insights and user journeys based on their shopping behavior

UX Designer, Patients & Purpose

New York, NY, November 2016 to October 2018

- Created wireframes, user flows and functional specs for projects with multinational pharmaceutical companies including desktop and mobile web sites and mobile apps
- Participated in the execution of usability studies, creating wireframes, clickable prototypes and user interview questions
- Spearheaded ongoing research on new approaches and ideas such as chatbots, progressive registration and voice user interactions for integration into new and ongoing work streams

Junior UX Designer, Bossa Digital

New York, NY, August 2013 to September 2016

- Designed responsive web wireframes and user flows for clients such as General Mills, Google & Target, as well as a Cannes Lion winning campaign for Coke Zero
- Created interactive prototypes of mobile designs for clients such as McDonalds, Coke Zero
 & Airbnb using Framer, InVision & Pixate

EDUCATION